Tom Raworth Papers 1974.0003
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Tom Raworth Papers
1964-1977
1974.0003
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
9.1 Linear feet
Born and raised in London, poet Tom Raworth travelled and worked in the United States and Mexico in the 1970s, returning to England in 1977 to be Resident Poet at King's College, Cambridge, the city in which he still lives. Since 1966 he has published more than forty books and pamphlets of poetry, prose and translations, in several countries. He was editor of three literary/art magazines: outburst (1961-63); Before Your Very Eyes! (1964); and Infolio (1986-87). During the 1960s he also ran two small presses - Matrix and Goliard. Since the early 1970s he has read his work in more than 20 countries.
Raworth, Tom
Biography
Tom Raworth was born and grew up in London. During the 1970s he travelled and worked in the United States and Mexico, returning to England in 1977 to be Resident Poet at King's College, Cambridge, in which city he still lives. Since 1966 he has published more than forty books and pamphlets of poetry, prose and translations, in several countries. His graphic work has been shown in France, Italy, and the USA, and he has collaborated and performed with musicians, painters, and other poets.
He was editor of three literary/art magazines: outburst (1961-63); Before Your Very Eyes! (1964); and Infolio (1986-87). During the 1960s he also ran two small presses - Matrix and Goliard. Since the early 1970s he has read his work in more than 20 countries, including at many International Literary Festivals, and has been invited to teach, or to be a visiting writer, in France, Italy, the USA, and the Republic of South Africa.
Tom Raworth's Collected Poems were published in 2003. His latest collection is Windmills in Flames: Old and New Poems (2010).
Scope and Content
The collection contains literary manuscripts, notebooks, correspondence received by Raworth, personal notes and fragments of writings, galleys, and some photographs. The bulk of the collection dates from 1972 to 1977.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Provenance and Acquisition
Acquired from Tom Raworth in 1974, 1976 and 1977.
Related Material
A substantial amount of Raworth correspondence resides in the Ed Dorn Papers and Charles Olson Research Collection in Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Hall, Barry; Olson, Charles, 1910-1970.; American poetry--20th century.; Correspondence.; Dorn, Edward—Correspondence.; English poetry—20th century.; Galley proofs.; Goliard Press.; Great Britain—Business, industries, and trades—Publishing.; Great Britain—Cultural affairs—Literature.; Literary Collections; London (England)—Business, industries, and trades—Publishing.; Londong (England)—Cultural affairs—Literature.; Manuscripts.; Matrix Press.; Notebooks.; Notes.; Outburst (Periodical); Periodical publishing Great Britain; Personal Papers.; Photographs.; Poems.; Poetry--Periodicals.; Poets, American--20th century.; Poets, American.; Publishers and publishing Great Britain
- Inventory
  - Box 1: Personal correspondence received by Raworth (A - Grady), 1964-1977 (Box 1)
    - A-C, 6 letters
    - Abbott, Ward, 1974-1975; 6 letters
    - Alpert, Barry, 1972-1976; 6 letters
    - Ball, David and Nicole, 1968-1974
    - Ball, David and Nicole, 1974
    - Ball, David, 1974-1975
    - Ball, David and Nicole, 1975-1977; 78 letters
    - Barrell, John, 1972-1976; 18 letters
    - Benveniste, Asa and Pip, 1972-1977; 39 letters
    - Berge, Carol, 1964-1976; 2 letters
    - Bergstrom, R.P., 1973
    - Berkson, Bill, 1973-1976; 5 letters
    - Berlin, Andrew, 1976-1977; 8 letters
    - Berrigan, Ted and Alice Notley, 1 letter
    - Bertolino, Jim?, 1973; 1 letter
    - Bertholf, Robert, 1974-1975; 2 letters
    - Blaisdell, Gus, 1973; 5 letters
    - Bokris, Victor, 1972-1973; 15 letters
    - Bowering, George, 1973-1977; 9 letters
    - Brainard, Joseph, 1972-1973; 3 letters
    - Brotherston, Gorden, 1974
    - Brown, Rebecca, 1973-1974; 4 letters
    - Butler, Bill, 1977; 1 letter
    - Butterfield, Penny and Herbie, 1973-1977; 38 letters
    - Butterick, George, 1974-1975; 16 letters
    - Byrd, Charles L., 1974; 1 letter
    - Calder, David, 1973; 1 letter
    - Caldwell, Claudia, 1975-1976; 2 letters
    - Callahan, Robert O., 1976; 1 letter
    - Carrigan, Andrew, 1973-1976; 20 letters
    - Chaloner, David, 1976; 1 letter
    - Clark, Tom, 1973-1974; 4 letters
    - Codrescu, Andrei, 1972-1975; 4 letters
    - Collom, Jack, 1975; 1 letter
    - Cox, Bill, 1973-1975; 8 letters
    - Creeley, Robert, 1975; 1 letter
    - Creighton, Jane, 1977; 1 letter
    - Crozier, Andrew, 1973; 2 letters
    - Cullingford, Angie, 1973; 1 letter
    - D-G, 8 letters
    - Daley, Debora
    - Daley, John, 1976; 2 letters
    - Dawson, Fielding, 1972-1977; 7 letters
    - DiPalma, Ray, 1972-1977; 28 letters
    - Dobbie, Michael, 1974; 2 letters
    - Dorn, Ed, 1969-1977; 24 letters
      Related Material
      See also correspondence from Ed Dorn to Raworth, 1960 to 1972, in Boxes 8 and 9.
    - Edwards, Edys, 1973-1977; 18 letters
    - Erickson, William E., 1972; 1 letter
    - Farkas, Zoltan, 1973; 1 letter
    - Faville, Curtis, 1973-1974; 3 letters
    - Fisher, Allen, 1974; 1 letter
    - Foster, Gilpin and Gayle, 1972-1977; 53 letters
    - Franco, Jean, 1972-1976; 4 letters
    - Gallup, Dick, 1973; 1 letter
    - Gates, Richard, 1974-1976; 8 letters
    - Gilfallen?, Merrill, 5 letters
    - Ginman, John, 1972-1973; 2 letters
    - Gitin, David and Maria, 1974; 1 letter
    - Gogarty, Paul, 1973-1975; 6 letters
    - Grady, Panna and Philip O'Connor, 1973-1974; 4 letters
  - Box 2: Personal correspondence received by Raworth (Grady - MacBeth), 1971-1977 (Box 2)
    - Graham, Jackie, 1973; 2 letters
    - Gray, Darrell, 1972-1977; 5 letters
    - Greenwald, Ted, 1972-1977; 56 letters
    - Greinke, Eric, 1974; 1 letter
    - Grenier, Bob, 1974; 1 letter
    - Hackman, Neil, 1974; 1 letter
    - H - K, 11 letters
    - Hall, Barry, 1973-1976; 25 letters
    - Hanson, Polly, 1972-1974; 2 letters
    - Harwood, Lee, 1972-1976; 5 letters
    - Hecht, Warren Jay, 1973; 2 letters
    - Helder, Jack, 1 letter
    - Heliczer, Piero, 1973; 3 letters
    - Henshaw, Marjorie B., 1973; 1 letter
    - Herd, Dale, 1975-1977; 11 letters
    - Hobson, Mike, 1977; 2 letters
    - Holl, Josie, 1975-1977; 4 letters
    - Hollo, Anselm, 1972-1976; 16 letters
    - Horovitz, Michael, 1972-1973; 13 letters
    - Ingham, Charles, 2 letters
    - Johnstone, Paul, 1976-1977; 4 letters
    - Jonathan Cape Ltd., 1973-1974; 3 letters
    - Kendall, Paul, 1972-1975; 8 letters
    - Khater, Tony, 2 letters
    - Knight, Arthur, 1974; 2 letters
    - Kodolanyi, Gyula, 1972-1976; 18 letters
    - Koperwas, Sam and Evelyn, 1973-1977; 23 letters
    - L- O, 7 letters
    - Lansdowne, Pat and Ken, 1973-1976; 4 letters
    - Larner, Jeremy, 1976-1977; 3 letters
    - Lesicka, Rene and Charlie, 1976-1977; 50 letters
    - Liddy, James, 1973; 1 letter
    - Little, Bill, 1 letter
    - Littlewood, Neil, 1975-1977; 51 letters
    - Lorenzo, 1976; 2 letters
    - Lowenfels, Walter, 1974; 1 letter
    - MacAdams, Lewis, 1974; 1 letter
    - MacBeth, George, 1974; 1 letter
  - Box 3: Personal correspondence received by Raworth (Maddux - Zephyrus, unknown), ephemera, and fragments, 1969-1977 (Box 3)
    - Maddux, Sam, 1974; 1 letter
    - Marley, Brian, 1973; 4 letters
    - Martin, John, 1974; 2 letters
    - Matthias, John, 1 letter
    - Mattingly, George, 1974-1976; 9 letters
    - Mayer, Bernadette, 1 letter
    - Mayor, David, 1974-1975; 1 letter
    - McClure, Michael, 1976; 1 letter
    - McCord, Howard, 1974; 1 letter
    - McEwen, Rory, 1974; 2 letters
    - McGough, Roger, 1974-1975; 3 letters
    - McNaughton, Duncan, 1974; 1 letter
    - McPhee, Patrick, 1976; 3 letters
    - Medhurst, Colin and Rosina, 1974-1976; 4 letters
    - Meltzer, David, 1969-1974; 4 letters
    - Mendleson, Anna and John, 1973-1977; 53 letters
    - Middleton, Christopher, 1973-1977; 6 letters
    - Montes de Oca, Ana Luisa, 1 letter
    - Mottram, Eric
    - Mulford, Wendy, 1977; 2 letters
    - Nations, Opal and Ellen, 1974-1975; 2 letters
    - Navero, Bud, 1976-1977; 3 letters
    - Neff, Severine, 1973; 3 letters
    - Negosanu, Petronela, 1976-1977; 11 letters
    - Nixson, Vivian, 1973-1976; 3 letters
    - Nuttall, Jeff, 1973-1976; 8 letters
    - O'Connor, Philip, 1976-1977; 2 letters
    - P-S, 17 letters
    - Pacheco, Jose and Christina, 1972-1977; 25 letters
    - Padgett, Ron, 1973-1974; 11 letters
    - Paul, John, 1974-1976; 8 letters
    - Pearson, Gabrielle, 1973; 3 letters
    - Pedroletti, Minouche, 1975; 2 letters
    - Pickard, Tom, 1977; 1 letter
    - Plomer, William, 1973; 2 letters
    - Poltroon Press, 1975-1976; 7 letters
    - Prynne, Jeremy, 1977; 1 letter
    - Randell, Elaine, 1973-1975; 20 letters
    - Rasulsa, Jed, 1976; 2 letters
    - Raworth, Mom and Dad, 1973-1977; 67 letters
    - Rezek, John, 1974; 1 letter
    - Robinson, Andrew, 1973-1974; 3 letters
    - Robinson, John, 1972-1973; 7 letters
    - Rodefer, Stephen, 1976; 2 letters
    - Rogers, Anne, 1973; 3 letters
    - Ross-Alter, Ivy, 1972-1977; 5 letters
    - Rouco, Maria de la Asuncion, 1973; 1 letter
    - Rowlen, B. R., 1973; 1 letter
    - Ruppert, Jim, 1 letter
    - Rusk, Robert, 1976; 2 letters
    - Silliman, Ronald, 1974; 2 letters
    - Sjoberg, John, 1973; 1 letter
    - Smith, Phil, 1974; 4 letters
    - Stangos, Nikos, 1972-1973; 2 letters
    - Symondson, William, 1 letter
    - T-Z
    - Telesis, Howard (H. Teter), 1 letter
    - Turnbull, Gael, 1977; 1 letter
    - Uren, Laurent
    - Uren, Sylvia
    - Veitch, Tom
    - Vincent, Steven
    - Vowles, Mike
    - Waldman, Anne
    - Walker, Nigel
    - Ward, Geoffrey
    - Watten, Barry
    - Welbourn, Bill
    - Weldon, William, 2 letters
    - Wevill, David
    - Whatman, Gaynor
    - Fang, Achilles, 1 letter
    - Wilhelm, Holly
    - Wilkinson, John and Jane
    - Williams, C. K.
    - Williams, Heathcote, 1974
    - Williams, Hugo
    - Williams, Jonathan
    - Young, Dudley
    - Young, Geoffrey
    - Zephyrus Image, 1976
    - Miscellaneous and unknown, 49 letters
    - Ephemera and Fragments
  - Box 4: Notebooks and manuscripts, 1970-1976 (Box 4)
    - Notebook, April - May 1972, July 19, 1972; includes inserts
    - Notebook "Austin Texas", August 29, 1974 - April 1975
    - Notebook "Scribe", August 1973 - May 23, 1974, October
    - Notebook "10/4/69", August 1973 to May 23, 1974, October 18, 19?
    - Notebook "Ball Point", July to August 1974
    - Notebook "Log Book", January 1, 1972 to March 1972
    - Notebook "Rowney", December 1970 to December 1971
    - Notebook, Rainbow Tablet, May to June 1973
    - Notebook, Rainbow Tablet, undated
    - Notebook, Rainbow Tablet, November 25, 1972 to ca. December 1972
    - Noetbook, green leaves (cover), September 1975, January to March 1976
    - Notebook, "July 18, 1973 Mexico"
    - Manuscripts (uncataloged)
  - Box 5: Manuscripts, fragments, and galley proofs, 1970-1975 (Box 5)
    - Folio, orange, Typescripts, loose
    - Folder "Rough", 1970 - 1972, 1974; Typescripts, handwritten manuscripts, fragments
    - "Correction proofs of ACT 6/21/75", 1975; Galleys with handwritten annotations
  - Box 6: Notebooks, manuscripts, and galley proofs, 1975-1977 (Box 6)
    - Notebook, black, undated
    - Notebook, blue, "San Francisco May 15, 1975", May 1975-June 1975
    - Notebook, cherub (cover), "San Francisco June 1/75", June 1975 - August 1975; includes inserts
    - Notebook "April/May 76", 1976
    - Notebook, weekly time book (cover), undated; Appears to be account book for correspondence
    - Address book, red (cover)
    - Notebook, blue paper (cover), "12/76", 1976
    - Notebook, brown hi-tone (cover), undated
    - Notebook, black and red (cover), "December '76", December 1976 to 1977?
    - Notebook, grey, "Sept 75", September 1975 to December 1975
    - Typescripts, loose, Manuscripts, notes, galley proofs
    - Binder "Writing (versions)", June to August 1975?
    - Tablet, Climax, ca. June 1975; Includes handwritten manuscripts
    - Typescripts, loose, Includes photocopy proof of ACE
  - Box 7: Artwork, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, photographs, clippings, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
  - Box 8: Correspondence from Ed Dorn to Raworth, February 12, 1960 to August 30, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Box 9: Correspondence from Ed Dorn to Raworth, January 11, 1966 to June 13, 1972, undated (Box 9)